# TAUFIK AJI PUTRA

+6289651017878 | taufikajiputra84@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/taufikajiputra | https://bit.ly/taufikajip

Kota Semarang, 50268

Final Year Statistics student who has a desire to keep learning new things, trying to improve, and doesn't get satisfied quickly. An undergraduate who seeks to learn in various sectors to apply the knowledge in Statistics and also to implement the work experience already gained.

## **Work Experiences**

## Compas.co.id (PT Telunjuk Komputasi Indonesia) - Jakarta,

Sep 2022 - Mar 2023

Indonesia

#### Data Admin Intern (Remote)

Compas comes from the same team that developed Telunjuk.com, a technology company in Jakarta, Indonesia. Compas focuses on business intelligence tools, for example, Market Insight of the e-commerce market, and provides actionable solutions to bring your business growth with the right business strategy.

- · Assist in conducting analysis, QA, and reporting crawled data conditions
- Assists in projects related to Al Data Science such as the Classification of product names in the marketplace
- Validate database data by paying attention to keywords, categories, segmentation, types, and benefits of product data in the marketplace using Google Data Studio and Google Sheets
- Accomplish manual data preprocessing by excluding 100+ influential outliers and anomalies daily using Google Data Studio and Google Sheets

## PT Telkom Indonesia Tbk - Semarang, Indonesia

Oct 2022 - Jan 2023

Data Analyst Intern

- Presents performance data with a dashboard system to simplify reports
- · Presents competitor sales data as material in providing business strategy
- · Analyze developments in social media trends and explore social media insight algorithms
- · Sentiment analysis for IndiHome products using social media insight tools

## YAASMIN - Sidoarjo, Indonesia

Jan 2022 - Apr 2022

### Data Entry Intern (Remote)

YAASMIN is a foundation that is engaged in social, humanitarian, and religious fields, by prioritizing information media and technology that can provide solutions to customers through products and services.

- Established good cooperation with approximately 70 interns in the Data Entry division
- Entered and validated approximately 30 job vacancies data in the company database.
- Coordinated with other divisions related to website management as a place for data input.

# Regional Financial and Asset Management Agency (BPKAD)

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

Pati Regency - Pati, Indonesia

Freelance Data Entry Assistant (Remote)

• Managed to enter approximately 60 taxpayer data into the management information system of the organization.

### **Education Level**

## **Diponegoro University - Semarang, Indonesia**

Aug 2019 - Feb 2023

Bachelor Degree in Statistics, 3.82/4.00

• Participate in various committee activities, organizations, and student activity units on campus.

# Hacktiv8 - Jakarta, Indonesia

Feb 2022 - Jun 2022

Certificate in Python for Data Science, 97.83/100.00

- Took part in learning with 16 subjects for approximately 5 months with the Asynchronous and Synchronous learning methods.
- Participated actively in the development of four final projects with each project having a team of two-three people accompanied by a mentor.

## Digital Skola - Jakarta, Indonesia

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

Certificate in Data Science, 93.00/100.00

- Took part in learning with 9 subjects for approximately 5 months with the Asynchronous and Synchronous learning methods.
- Participated actively in the development of two final projects with a team of five persons accompanied by a mentor.

# Organisational Experience

### Head of Communication and Information Department

- · Responsible for managing and supervising the activities in the Communication and Information Department.
- Initiated the use of the most up-to-date mass communication media for the organization.
- · Conceptualized the major activities that must be carried out online, and accomplished to achieve the expected target.
- · Contributed to the activities of Himasta Undip in general,

### Himasta Undip - Semarang, Indonesia

Feb 2020 - Dec 2020

### Staff of Communication and Information Department

- Assigned to make videos about Himasta Undip activities and responsible for managing content on the website. I have managed to
  make an organization profile video, 7 post-show videos, 6 podcast episodes in 2 types for IGTV and Youtube, also 2 general videos in
  2020 for a year on Himasta Undip Youtube Channel.
- Contributed to the activities of Himasta Undip in general, such as editing posters, and videos, and also became an MC of internal and external events.

## Skills, Achievements & Other Experience

- Skills: Ms. Office, Google Suites, SPSS, Minitab, R, Python, Google Data Studio, Canva, Adobe Photoshop, Filmora
- Interest: Data Science, Data Analyst, Data Entry, Social Media, Basic Design, Digital Marketing
- Projects @: Data Science Modelling Project from Digital Skola (2021), Python for Data Science Final Project from Hacktiv8 (2022)
- Achievements: Best Mentee of the Month (October) by Digistar Regional Internship Batch 5 (2022), Best Techies of the Month by Digital Skola (2021), Winner of the Scholastic Potential Test Olympiad by Tembus.FK (2019)
- Languages ⊚: Indonesian (Native), English (Intermediate)